<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Emino.App&#39;s, Art&#39;s &amp; Articles by Emin Mahrt</title>
    <link>https://emino.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emino.App&#39;s, Art&#39;s &amp; Articles by Emin Mahrt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:50:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://emino.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Post</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/untitled-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/untitled-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dar-es-salaam-needs-a-worldclass-safe-dance-space&#34;&gt;Dar es Salaam Needs a World‑Class Safe Dance Space&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-open-call-to-artists-djs-producers-architects-sound&#34;&gt;An open call to artists, DJs, producers, architects, sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;engineers, and cultural organisers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dar es Salaam is not “the next big city.” It’s &lt;strong&gt;the city that is
already arriving&lt;/strong&gt;—fast.
The question is whether the cultural infrastructure will arrive with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Dar es Salaam Region has &lt;strong&gt;5,383,728 people (2022 census)&lt;/strong&gt;—up
from &lt;strong&gt;4,364,541 in 2012&lt;/strong&gt;. Youth dominate the population: &lt;strong&gt;37.1% are
below 18&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;21.9% are 15–24&lt;/strong&gt;. The median age is &lt;strong&gt;23.1&lt;/strong&gt;.
That means: millions of teenagers and young adults are coming of age
&lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;—and the city urgently needs safe, well‑run spaces where
they can gather, dance, learn, create, and belong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spark Wallet UX &#43; Lightning Flow — Chronological Build Log</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/spark-wallet-ux-lightning-flow-chronological-build-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/spark-wallet-ux-lightning-flow-chronological-build-log/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;spark-wallet-ux--lightning-flow--chronological-build-log&#34;&gt;Spark Wallet UX + Lightning Flow — Chronological Build Log&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;briefing-and-constraints&#34;&gt;Briefing and Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You asked for the Spark wallet to look exactly like the existing
Bitcoin screen, keep code minimal, and avoid duplicate/legacy code.
You also set strict process rules: no git commands, no tests,
approvals before implementation, and short, precise responses. You
wanted the receive/send flow to mirror Bitcoin UI and to support
Lightning invoices, LNURL, and
later onchain withdrawals from Spark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump Doctrine and the Fall of Maduro: A New Era of Gunboat Diplomacy?</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-trump-doctrine-and-the-fall-of-maduro-a-new-era-of-gunbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-trump-doctrine-and-the-fall-of-maduro-a-new-era-of-gunbo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-trump-doctrine-and-the-fall-of-maduro-a-new-era-of-gunboat-diplomacy&#34;&gt;The Trump Doctrine and the Fall of Maduro: A New Era of Gunboat Diplomacy?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dramatic events of January 3, 2026, when Venezuelan President
Nicolás Maduro was removed from his residence in Caracas, have sent
shockwaves through the international community. In a profound
analysis, PLO Lumumba explores the implications of this action,
framing it as the &amp;ldquo;death of international law&amp;rdquo; and the birth of a
starkly unilateral &amp;ldquo;Trump Doctrine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-rehash-of-gunboat-diplomacy&#34;&gt;A Rehash of Gunboat Diplomacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lumumba argues that the removal of Maduro is a modern manifestation of
the Monroe Doctrine, updated for the 21st century. He suggests that
while the 19th-century doctrine targeted European powers, the current
&lt;strong&gt;Trump Doctrine&lt;/strong&gt; asserts absolute American hegemony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Song That Burned Down a Republic: The Story of Fela Kuti&#39;s Zombie</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-song-that-burned-down-a-republic-the-story-of-fela-kuti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-song-that-burned-down-a-republic-the-story-of-fela-kuti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;In 1976, Fela Kuti released &amp;quot;Zombie,&amp;quot; a scathing musical attack on the Nigerian military. The retaliation was swift and brutal. Below is the full story as presented in the documentary video, followed by the complete lyrics and verified historical context.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **TL;DR**&lt;br&gt;Fela Kuti&amp;#x27;s &amp;quot;Zombie&amp;quot; mocked soldiers as mindless robots. In retaliation, 1,000 soldiers stormed his Kalakuta Republic commune, burning it to the ground and throwing his mother from a window. This post contains the full explanatory text from the video, the complete song lyrics, and confirmed historical facts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **1. The Full Story (As Written in the Video)**&lt;br&gt;*The following text appears as on-screen overlays in the video documentation of the event:*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;The fury stirred up among the Nigerian police and military by Fela&amp;#x27;s furiously confrontational albums Alagbon Close in 1974 and Kalakuta Show in 1976, and the beatings and harassments Fela and Africa 70 suffered as a consequence, were as nothing compared to the reprisals following a later 1976 album, Zombie...&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Within months of its release, a large-scale army attack left Fela&amp;#x27;s Kalakuta Republic compound burnt to the ground, and many of its occupants, including Fela, assaulted and seriously injured. The sacking of Kalakuta was not, of course, brought about only by Zombie, but in the tension then existing between Fela and the military, it raised the temperature to boiling point.&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;On &amp;#x27;Zombie&amp;#x27; itself, over an urgent, quick-march accompaniment from Afrika 70, Fela and the backup singers ridicule the mindset of men in uniform. &amp;#x27;Attention! Quick march! Slow march! Salute!&amp;#x27; sings Fela, &amp;#x27;Fall in! Fall out! Fall down! Go and kill! Go and die! Go and quench!&amp;#x27; Each phrase is followed by the women singers&amp;#x27; taunting response, &amp;#x27;Zombie!&amp;#x27;&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Fela continues: &amp;#x27;No brains, no job, no sense joro jara jo; tell am to go kill joro jara jo; tell am to go quench joro jara jo (meaning,&amp;quot;no brains, no job, no sense left right left&amp;quot;; tell him to go kill left right left; tell him to go die left right left.&amp;quot;)&amp;#x27;&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;For the army, Fela&amp;#x27;s lyrics were the final insult, a direct attack on its pride and prestige, and probably more wounding for the fact that it was being made to look foolish, in part, by women. Worse still, Zombie was a hit across Africa, adding an international dimension to the insult. The army&amp;#x27;s response was terrible....&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;On 18 February, 1977, around 1,000 soldiers, most of them armed, swooped on Fela&amp;#x27;s Kalakuta Republic compound. They cordoned off the surrounding area, broke down the wire fence around the community&amp;#x27;s buildings, and battered their way into the central structure. Occupants were stripped and barbarously abused; particularly unfortunate men had their testicles beaten with rifle butts; particularly unfortunate women were raped (one also had her nipples crushed with stones)....&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Fela was badly beaten, sustaining a fractured skull and several broken bones. His mother, then aged 77, was thrown out of a window, fracturing a leg and suffering deep trauma. The army then set fire to the compound and prevented the fire brigade reaching the area....&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;The ensuing blaze gutted the premises, destroying six Afrika 70 vehicles, all the master tapes and band equipment, a four-track recording studio, all the community members&amp;#x27; belongings and, for good measure, the free medical clinic run by Fela&amp;#x27;s brother, Dr Beko Ransome Kuti (who was also severely beaten in the attack)....&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;The first journalists to arrive on the scene were assaulted by soldiers. Inquisitive passers-by were similarly set upon. The army didn&amp;#x27;t want any witnesses. They were unsuccessful at least in that; photographs of the fire and its immediate aftermath appeared in the Nigerian press within days.&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;But Fela&amp;#x27;s political stance didn&amp;#x27;t endear itself to the Ghanaian authorities either - particularly when protesting Ghanaian students starting shouting &amp;quot;Zombie!&amp;quot; at police and soldiers in the streets. After a few turbulent months, Fela was sent back to Nigeria.&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **2. The Song Text (Full Lyrics)**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Chorus (Call &amp;amp; Response)**&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Zombie o, zombie *(Zombie o, zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Zombie o, zombie *(Zombie o, zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Verse 1**&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Zombie no go go, unless you tell am to go *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Zombie no go stop, unless you tell am to stop *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Zombie no go turn, unless you tell am to turn *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Zombie no go think, unless you tell am to think *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Verse 2**&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Tell am to go straight&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *A joro, jara, joro*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; No brake, no job, no sense&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *A joro, jara, joro*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Tell am to go kill&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *A joro, jara, joro*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; No brake, no job, no sense&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *A joro, jara, joro*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Tell am to go quench&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *A joro, jara, joro*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; No brake, no job, no sense&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *A joro, jara, joro*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Bridge**&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Go and kill! *(Joro, jara, joro)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Go and die! *(Joro, jara, joro)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Go and quench! *(Joro, jara, joro)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Put am for reverse! *(Joro, jara, joro)*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Outro (Military Commands)**&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Attention! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Quick march! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Slow march! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Left turn! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Right turn! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; About turn! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Double up! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Salute! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Open your hat! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Stand at ease! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Fall in! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Fall out! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Fall down! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Get ready! *(Zombie)*&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Halt! Order!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **3. Historical Facts &amp;amp; Verification**&lt;br&gt;*Additional research confirms and expands on the events described in the video:*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* **The Date:** The attack definitively occurred on **February 18, 1977**.&lt;br&gt;* **The Scale:** Historical records confirm approximately **1,000 soldiers** were involved in the raid.&lt;br&gt;* **The Mother:** Fela&amp;#x27;s mother, **Funmilayo Ransome-Kuti**, was a famous suffragist and political activist. She died in 1978 from complications related to the injuries sustained when she was thrown from the window during this raid.&lt;br&gt;* **The &amp;quot;Unknown Soldier&amp;quot;:** Following the destruction, an official inquiry claimed the compound was burned by &amp;quot;an unknown soldier,&amp;quot; absolving the military hierarchy of direct responsibility. This verdict led Fela to record the song &amp;quot;Unknown Soldier&amp;quot; in response.&lt;br&gt;* **The Ghana Incident:** The video mentions Fela being sent back from Ghana. This happened in 1978; he was banned from the country after riots broke out during a performance of &amp;quot;Zombie&amp;quot; in Accra.&lt;br&gt;* **The Coffin:** In a final act of defiance, Fela and his movement carried a symbolic coffin to the Dodan Barracks in Lagos to protest his mother&amp;#x27;s death.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---
*Post created via email from emin@nuri.com*</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Post</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/untitled-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 06:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/untitled-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

![IMG_7629](/media/untitled-post/IMG_7629.jpg)

---
*Post created via email from emin@nuri.com*</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Playbook: 9 Mental Models for Building in the Age of Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-ai-playbook-9-mental-models-for-building-in-the-age-of-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-ai-playbook-9-mental-models-for-building-in-the-age-of-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The AI Playbook: 9 Mental Models for Building in the Age of Intelligence
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7xTGNNLPyMI&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7xTGNNLPyMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not your typical founder story. This is a masterclass from the
&amp;ldquo;Teacher of the AI Revolution.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrej Karpathy (founding member of OpenAI, former Director of AI at
Tesla) just dropped a 3.5-hour &amp;ldquo;State of the Union&amp;rdquo; on Large Language
Models. If you are building a startup today, you cannot afford to
ignore this. This is the new electricity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $40 Billion Secret: 9 Lessons from the Chocolate King Who Built an Empire in the Shadows</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-40-billion-secret-9-lessons-from-the-chocolate-king-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-40-billion-secret-9-lessons-from-the-chocolate-king-who/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The $40 Billion Secret: 9 Lessons from the Chocolate King Who Built an
Empire in the Shadows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ksDrpn7yNEo?si=rpE0EIQJnxp-74Ze&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/ksDrpn7yNEo?si=rpE0EIQJnxp-74Ze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be one of the most incredible founder stories you will ever hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 70 years, Michele Ferrero was the &amp;ldquo;Willy Wonka&amp;rdquo; of the real
world—a reclusive, obsessive Italian billionaire who built a privately
owned, debt-free, $40 billion empire (Ferrero Group) that owns
Nutella, Tic Tac, Kinder, and Ferrero Rocher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He never gave interviews. He wore dark sunglasses. He hid in his
laboratory. And he repeated the same maxims to his employees 60 times
a week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aave DAO&#39;s Governance Showdown: The Fight for Brand Ownership and Token Alignment</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/aave-dao-s-governance-showdown-the-fight-for-brand-ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/aave-dao-s-governance-showdown-the-fight-for-brand-ownership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;**TL;DR**  &lt;br&gt;Aave DAO is voting on a controversial proposal to transfer control of core brand assets (domains, social handles, GitHub repos, etc.) from Aave Labs to the DAO. Supporters see it as essential for true decentralization and revenue alignment; opponents argue it risks inefficiency and hurts innovation. The vote, rushed to Snapshot amid heated debate, has sparked accusations of bad faith, with $AAVE price dipping ~7-10% amid uncertainty. Voting ends December 25, 2025.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Introduction&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Aave, the leading DeFi lending protocol with over $50B+ TVL and ~60% market share in on-chain lending, faces an existential governance crisis. The proposal &amp;quot;[ARFC] $AAVE token alignment. Phase 1 – Ownership&amp;quot; ([Snapshot link](&lt;a href=&#34;https://snapshot.org/#/s:aavedao.eth/proposal/0xbc606159ddeae0184c2086055637d3f357351ec0adc4c9f4150751bc41918eba&#34;&gt;https://snapshot.org/#/s:aavedao.eth/proposal/0xbc606159ddeae0184c2086055637d3f357351ec0adc4c9f4150751bc41918eba&lt;/a&gt;)) seeks to shift explicit ownership of Aave&amp;#x27;s brand assets to the DAO via a neutral legal wrapper (e.g., a Cayman foundation).  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Authored by Ernesto Boado (co-founder of BGD Labs and former Aave CTO), it was escalated to Snapshot on December 22, 2025, by Aave Labs despite objections from the author and some delegates. Voting runs until December 25, 2025.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Proposal Details&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- **Assets in Scope**: Domains (&lt;a href=&#34;http://aave.com&#34;&gt;aave.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://app.aave.com&#34;&gt;app.aave.com&lt;/a&gt;), social handles, naming rights, GitHub organizations, NPM namespaces.  &lt;br&gt;- **Goal**: Replace &amp;quot;implicit stewardship&amp;quot; by Aave Labs with DAO-controlled ownership, including anti-capture protections.  &lt;br&gt;- **Rationale**: Prevent private monetization (e.g., frontend swap fees) and ensure value accrues to $AAVE holders.  &lt;br&gt;- **Implementation**: Phase 1 is principle-only; Phase 2 will define legal structure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Source: [Aave Governance Forum Thread](&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/arfc-aave-token-alignment-phase-1-ownership/23616&#34;&gt;https://governance.aave.com/t/arfc-aave-token-alignment-phase-1-ownership/23616&lt;/a&gt;) and [Snapshot Proposal](&lt;a href=&#34;https://snapshot.org/#/s:aavedao.eth/proposal/0xbc606159ddeae0184c2086055637d3f357351ec0adc4c9f4150751bc41918eba&#34;&gt;https://snapshot.org/#/s:aavedao.eth/proposal/0xbc606159ddeae0184c2086055637d3f357351ec0adc4c9f4150751bc41918eba&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Arguments in Favor&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Supporters argue that token holders funded Aave via ICO and deserve explicit ownership.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Who owns AAVE? ... The token holders. Full stop.&amp;quot;  &lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; — Tor_GAINS, Snapshot discussion&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Prominent voices like Jordan (former Aave COO) emphasize returning to the original vision:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;This is the natural next step in Aave’s decentralization... especially now that DeFi benefits from far more regulatory clarity.&amp;quot;  &lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; — Jordan, Aave Governance Forum&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Others highlight misalignment risks, such as CoW Swap integration diverting referral fees or Horizon market (a Labs-led product) allocating only 15% revenue to DAO.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Arguments Against&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Opponents, including Aave Labs founder Stani Kulechov, warn of operational paralysis.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;The recent DAO alignment proposal has been moved to Snapshot after extensive discussion... Time for tokenholders to weigh in and vote.&amp;quot;  &lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; — Stani Kulechov (@StaniKulechov), X post (Dec 22, 2025)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Labs representatives argue the current model works, and DAO control introduces bureaucracy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Is the path forward... for decentralized entities... to look and act more like centralized entities?&amp;quot;  &lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; — setaavefree, Snapshot discussion&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Critics also note timing issues (holiday season) and lack of consensus.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Key Drama and Controversies&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- **Rushed Escalation**: Author Ernesto Boado disavowed the Snapshot submission:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  &amp;gt; &amp;quot;This is not, in ethos, my proposal... Trying to rush a vote is disgraceful.&amp;quot;  &lt;br&gt;  &amp;gt; — Ernesto Boado (@eboadom), X post (Dec 22, 2025)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- **ACI Response**: Marc Zeller (Aave Chan Initiative) called it &amp;quot;unprecedented interference.&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  &amp;gt; &amp;quot;We acknowledge @aave unilaterally escalated the proposal... Worst outcome that was entirely preventable.&amp;quot;  &lt;br&gt;  &amp;gt; — Marc Zeller (@Marczeller), X post (Dec 22, 2025)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- **Community Sentiment on X**: Polarized. Some accuse Labs of &amp;quot;stealth privatization&amp;quot;; others defend Labs&amp;#x27; contributions. Recent X discussions highlight frustration over revenue sharing and governance process.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Technical and DeFi Implications&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This vote tests **DAO vs. founder-led hybrid models** in DeFi. Aave&amp;#x27;s success stems from Labs&amp;#x27; rapid iteration (e.g., V3, GHO stablecoin at 350M+ supply, Horizon for RWA onboarding). However:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- **Revenue Split**: Protocol fees (~$100M+ annually) go to DAO; frontend/app monetization often benefits Labs.&lt;br&gt;- **Legal Challenges**: DAOs need wrappers (e.g., DUNAs, foundations) for IP ownership.&lt;br&gt;- **Precedents**: Echoes Uniswap&amp;#x27;s recent alignment shifts, but Aave&amp;#x27;s hybrid has driven dominance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If passed, it could force Labs to license the brand or negotiate revenue shares. If rejected, it reinforces Labs&amp;#x27; autonomy but risks further backlash.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Current Market Impact&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;$AAVE trades around $160–$180 (as of Dec 22, 2025), down ~7–10% amid drama. Predictions vary: short-term bearish (Fear &amp;amp; Greed at Extreme Fear), but long-term bullish if resolved positively.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sources: [CoinGecko](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/aave&#34;&gt;https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/aave&lt;/a&gt;), [Bitget](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitget.com/price/aave/price-prediction&#34;&gt;https://www.bitget.com/price/aave/price-prediction&lt;/a&gt;), [CoinCodex](&lt;a href=&#34;https://coincodex.com/crypto/aave-token/price-prediction/&#34;&gt;https://coincodex.com/crypto/aave-token/price-prediction/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## Conclusion&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This governance battle highlights DeFi&amp;#x27;s maturation pains: balancing decentralization with execution speed. Aave remains the lending king, but unresolved alignment risks eroding trust. Token holders decide December 25—will it reinforce DAO sovereignty or preserve Labs&amp;#x27; operational edge? The outcome will shape not just Aave, but the future of founder-DAO relations in DeFi.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---
*Post created via email from emin@nuri.com*</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Aave Governance Crisis: A Technical Post-Mortem of Proposal 0xbc60</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-aave-governance-crisis-a-technical-post-mortem-of-propos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-aave-governance-crisis-a-technical-post-mortem-of-propos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;### **Abstract**&lt;br&gt;In late December 2025, the Aave DAO faced its most significant existential challenge since the protocol&amp;#x27;s inception. What began as a technical debate over revenue attribution from the `&lt;a href=&#34;http://app.aave.com&#34;&gt;app.aave.com&lt;/a&gt;` frontend devolved into a &amp;quot;hostile takeover&amp;quot; accusation, creating a precedent-setting case study on the decoupling of **Protocol (Immutable Code)** and **Product (Mutable Brand)**. This document analyzes the 164-post governance thread, the unilateral escalation to Snapshot, and the broader implications for decentralized governance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **1. The Inciting Incident: The &amp;quot;Implicit Agreement&amp;quot; Breaks**&lt;br&gt;For years, the Aave ecosystem operated on a handshake understanding: **Aave Labs** (formerly Aave Companies, led by Stani Kulechov) acted as the steward of the brand, while the **DAO** (Token Holders) governed the protocol. This alignment fractured when Aave Labs integrated **CowSwap** into the official frontend, directing the surplus/referral revenue to their own corporate entity rather than the DAO treasury.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**The Economic Reality:**&lt;br&gt;* **Protocol Revenue:** Accrues to the DAO (Reserve Factors).&lt;br&gt;* **Frontend Revenue:** Historically undefined/negligible, now estimated at **$10M+ annualized** via swap fees and integrations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**The Community Reaction:**&lt;br&gt;Token holders, led by large delegates like **EzR3aL** and **Marc Zeller (Aave Chan Initiative)**, argued this was a breach of fiduciary duty. If the DAO funded the protocol&amp;#x27;s development (via the 2017 ICO and grants), why should a private entity capture the frontend value?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *&amp;quot;It seems we have been fooled in considering this a natural alignment, and we acknowledge the new reality... When you own $AAVE, what do you actually own?&amp;quot;* — **Marc Zeller (ACI)**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **2. The Proposal: &amp;quot;Token Alignment Phase 1 - Ownership&amp;quot;**&lt;br&gt;**Author:** Ernesto Boado (`@eboado`), Co-founder of BGD Labs (Aave&amp;#x27;s Core Tech Service Provider).&lt;br&gt;**Date:** Dec 16, 2025&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Boado published a proposal to formalize the separation of concerns. The core argument was technical and legal: **A DAO cannot be autonomous if it relies on a private &amp;quot;benevolent dictator&amp;quot; for its public face.**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**The Proposed Architecture:**&lt;br&gt;1.  **Asset Transfer:** Transfer &amp;quot;Soft Assets&amp;quot; (Domains `&lt;a href=&#34;http://aave.com&#34;&gt;aave.com&lt;/a&gt;`, Social Handles `@aave`, Trademarks, GitHub Orgs) to a **DAO-Controlled Legal Wrapper** (e.g., a Cayman Foundation).&lt;br&gt;2.  **Licensing Model:** The DAO would then *license* these assets back to service providers (including Aave Labs) under strict, enforceable terms.&lt;br&gt;3.  **Anti-Capture:** &amp;quot;Strict mechanisms so that no third party can misuse these assets or privately benefit from them.&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *&amp;quot;Not having a resolution on this issue is an existential threat to the DAO model... If a single party can control soft assets like brand, marketing channels, and gateways... all other contributors become de facto subordinated to that party.&amp;quot;* — **Ernesto Boado (Post #1)**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **3. The Counter-Argument: Product vs. Protocol**&lt;br&gt;While Aave Labs did not engage deeply in text battles on the forum, their actions and supported arguments outlined a clear defense: **Composability and Corporate Rights.**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* **The &amp;quot;Neobank&amp;quot; Vision:** Stani Kulechov envisions Aave Labs building a consumer-facing fintech product (&amp;quot;Aave Horizon&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Aave App&amp;quot;) that competes with Revolut or Monzo.&lt;br&gt;* **The Separation:** They argue `&lt;a href=&#34;http://app.aave.com&#34;&gt;app.aave.com&lt;/a&gt;` is a proprietary product built *on top* of the protocol. Just as `Instadapp` or `DeFi Saver` don&amp;#x27;t pay royalties to the Aave DAO for using the protocol, Aave Labs believes they have the right to monetize their specific frontend interface.&lt;br&gt;* **Operational Efficiency:** A DAO is too slow to manage a consumer brand. A centralized entity is required for agility in the fintech sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *&amp;quot;The Aave protocol, as a series of smart contracts governed by a DAO, is unconventional... Aave the protocol doesn&amp;#x27;t need to own a website, a domain name, or even a brand. It exists in perfect and pure form without any of those.&amp;quot;* — **setaavefree (Post #11)**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **4. The Escalation: &amp;quot;Shadow Governance&amp;quot;**&lt;br&gt;On **December 22, 2025**, the debate shifted from a forum discussion to a governance crisis. Aave Labs used their administrative privileges to unilaterally push Boado&amp;#x27;s proposal to a Snapshot vote, **bypassing the author** and the standard feedback loop.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**The Technical Violation:**&lt;br&gt;* **Timing:** The vote was scheduled for Dec 23, deep into the holiday season when institutional delegates are less active.&lt;br&gt;* **Consent:** The proposal author (Boado) explicitly stated he did *not* approve the text for voting.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**The Fallout (Post #120-130):**&lt;br&gt;The forum exploded with accusations of a &amp;quot;Hostile Takeover.&amp;quot; The market responded with a **~10% drop in $AAVE price** and a $37M whale sell-off, pricing in the governance risk.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *&amp;quot;To be very clear about it: Aave Labs has, for some reason, decided to rush to vote unilaterally my proposal... This type of action breaks all types of trust... For me, the current Snapshot proposal created by Labs is nonexistent.&amp;quot;* — **Ernesto Boado (Post #124)**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; *&amp;quot;This did not have to escalate this way... What started as a push for clarity... is now turning into a hostile takeover attempt by Labs.&amp;quot;* — **Marc Zeller (Post #123)**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Aave Labs&amp;#x27; Defense:**&lt;br&gt;Stani Kulechov argued on X (formerly Twitter) and via spokespeople that the &amp;quot;extensive discussion&amp;quot; (5 days) was sufficient and that &amp;quot;voting is the best way to resolve&amp;quot; the gridlock.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **5. Technical Analysis: The &amp;quot;Wrapper&amp;quot; Solution**&lt;br&gt;The debate highlights a critical flaw in current DAO architectures: **The Missing Link between On-Chain Code and Off-Chain IP.**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;| **Component** | **Current State** | **Proposed State (Wrapper)** |&lt;br&gt;| :--- | :--- | :--- |&lt;br&gt;| **Smart Contracts** | Owned by Token Holders (Timelock) | Owned by Token Holders (Timelock) |&lt;br&gt;| **Domain (DNS)** | Owned by Aave Labs (Private Co) | Owned by DAO Legal Wrapper |&lt;br&gt;| **Frontend Code** | Closed Source / Private | Licensed to DAO or Open Source |&lt;br&gt;| **Revenue Stream** | Split (Protocol=DAO, Frontend=Labs) | Unified or Strictly Licensed |&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**The &amp;quot;Poison Pill&amp;quot; Threat:**&lt;br&gt;Some delegates (Post #113, #118) discussed extreme measures, such as forking the frontend, redirecting liquidity incentives to a new DAO-owned frontend, or even &amp;quot;hiring&amp;quot; a new development team to replace Aave Labs entirely. This demonstrates that while the *code* is immutable, the *social consensus* is highly volatile.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### **Conclusion**&lt;br&gt;The 164-post thread of Proposal 0xbc60 serves as a warning to all maturity-phase DAOs. The **&amp;quot;Implicit Agreement&amp;quot;**—that founders will always act in the DAO&amp;#x27;s best interest—is a single point of failure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* **If the DAO votes YES:** It forces a legal confrontation over IP transfer, potentially leading to a fork if Aave Labs refuses to comply.&lt;br&gt;* **If the DAO votes NO:** It establishes a precedent that &amp;quot;Service Providers&amp;quot; can capture the protocol&amp;#x27;s frontend value, effectively demoting the DAO to a backend infrastructure provider with no control over its customer relationship.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Final Verdict:** The decentralized finance stack is composable, but **trust is not.**&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---
*Post created via email from emin@nuri.com*</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>⚖️ Code is Law vs. The $9.4M Rescue: The Gnosis Chain Hard Fork</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/code-is-law-vs-the-9-4m-rescue-the-gnosis-chain-hard-fork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/code-is-law-vs-the-9-4m-rescue-the-gnosis-chain-hard-fork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Event:&lt;/strong&gt; In December 2025, Gnosis Chain executed a controversial
hard fork to recover &lt;strong&gt;$9.4M&lt;/strong&gt; stolen in the Balancer protocol hack.
&lt;strong&gt;The Conflict:&lt;/strong&gt; The decision pitted &amp;ldquo;Pragmatists&amp;rdquo; (who prioritize
victim restitution and mass adoption) against &amp;ldquo;Purists&amp;rdquo; (who fear the
loss of credible neutrality and censorship resistance).
&lt;strong&gt;The Outcome:&lt;/strong&gt; The chain successfully seized the hacker&amp;rsquo;s funds, but
the process bypassed the DAO vote, revealing that technical governance
currently outweighs community governance in crises. A new
&amp;ldquo;Intervention Framework&amp;rdquo; is being drafted to prevent arbitrary
decisions in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Feature Code Review of Nuri.com</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/ai-feature-code-review-of-nuri-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/ai-feature-code-review-of-nuri-com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on my analysis of the Nuri Expo app, here are all the
user-facing features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin Wallet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send/receive Bitcoin transactions
Lightning network support
QR code scanning for payments
Bitcoin balance display
Transaction history&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Euro Card (Gnosis Pay)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical and virtual debit card
EURe (Euro stablecoin) balance
Card transactions history
Add money to card via bank transfer
Order physical cards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fiat Banking (Monerium Integration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBAN transfers
Bank account details
Euro deposits/withdrawals
Transaction history&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resident Advisor Exchange: An Interview with Ricardo Villalobos (2012)</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/resident-advisor-exchange-an-interview-with-ricardo-villalob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/resident-advisor-exchange-an-interview-with-ricardo-villalob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resident-advisor-exchange-ricardo-villalobos&#34;&gt;Resident Advisor Exchange: Ricardo Villalobos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host:&lt;/strong&gt; Todd L. Burns
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Broadcast approx. 2012 (RA Exchange 100)
&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/ra-exchange/ra-exchange-100&#34;&gt;Resident
Advisor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro:&lt;/strong&gt; Hello, and welcome to Resident Advisor&amp;rsquo;s Exchange, a series of conversations with the artists, labels, and promoters that are shaping the electronic music landscape. My name is Todd L. Burns, and I&amp;rsquo;m the Editor-in-Chief of Resident Advisor. For our 100th RA Exchange, I spoke to Chilean-born, German-bred DJ and producer Ricardo Villalobos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cryptographically Safe Method for Zero-Confirmation Bitcoin Acceptance</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/a-cryptographically-safe-method-for-zero-confirmation-bitcoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/a-cryptographically-safe-method-for-zero-confirmation-bitcoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin transactions are not final until confirmed in a block. Any
transaction spending a given UTXO can be replaced by another valid
transaction spending the same inputs until one is confirmed. This
makes generic zero-confirmation acceptance unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document describes a construction that allows a service to safely
accept and act upon a zero-confirmation Bitcoin transaction, in the
sense that the payer cannot create a conflicting valid transaction
during a defined window. The construction relies on enforcing signing
authority at the UTXO level and does not depend on mempool behavior or
miner policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stateless Bitcoin Multisig: Divergent Key Derivation Strategies</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/stateless-bitcoin-multisig-divergent-key-derivation-strategi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/stateless-bitcoin-multisig-divergent-key-derivation-strategi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the implementation of non-custodial Bitcoin wallets utilizing
MuSig2 and WebAuthn (Passkeys), &amp;ldquo;statelessness&amp;rdquo; defines the
architectural constraint. The system must reconstruct key material
deterministically without relying on ephemeral state. However, the
cryptographic source of truth for the server-side co-signer presents
two distinct architectural paradigms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post analyzes the transition from a Client-Entropy Model to a
Hybrid-Entropy Model and the resulting determinism challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-architecture-a-the-client-entropy-model-pure-prf&#34;&gt;1. Architecture A: The Client-Entropy Model (Pure PRF)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legacy architecture prioritizes portability and zero-knowledge
properties on the server side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuri Wallet: A Stateless MuSig2 Bitcoin Wallet with Decaying Multisig Recovery</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/nuri-wallet-a-stateless-musig2-bitcoin-wallet-with-decaying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/nuri-wallet-a-stateless-musig2-bitcoin-wallet-with-decaying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Work in Progress. Document written by Opus 4.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-design-document&#34;&gt;Technical Design Document&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuri Wallet is a next-generation Bitcoin wallet that combines &lt;strong&gt;MuSig2
Schnorr signatures&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;stateless key derivation via WebAuthn PRF&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;NFC hardware wallet integration&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;server-assisted two-factor
authentication&lt;/strong&gt; into a unified security architecture. The design
prioritizes both security and recoverability through a &lt;strong&gt;decaying
multisig&lt;/strong&gt; mechanism that ensures users can always recover their
funds, even if one or more signing components become unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Die unendliche Geschichte des Universums</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/die-unendliche-geschichte-des-universums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/die-unendliche-geschichte-des-universums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Die unendliche Geschichte des Universums&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ein philosophisch-mathematisches Gedankenexperiment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR (Zusammenfassung)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dieses Gedankenexperiment hinterfragt den Urknall als festen Startpunkt. Stattdessen wird vorgeschlagen, dass der &amp;quot;Anfang&amp;quot; des Universums mathematisch einer Asymptote gleicht (ähnlich der Zahl Pi), die man nie erreichen kann. Das Universum basiert demnach auf einem ewigen Kreislauf, in dem Schwarze Löcher Materie recyceln und als Strahlung wieder emittieren – ein Prozess, der Parallelen zu modernen Theorien wie dem &amp;quot;Big Bounce&amp;quot; oder der &amp;quot;Konformen Zyklischen Kosmologie&amp;quot; aufweist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No True Beginning and Infinite Regression</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/no-true-beginning-and-infinite-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/no-true-beginning-and-infinite-regression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-idea-of-the-beginning-of-the-universe&#34;&gt;My Idea of the Beginning of the Universe:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a question about the beginning of the universe. If we look at
the universe as some sort like the Big Bang, and I don&amp;rsquo;t say it&amp;rsquo;s a
dot, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually something like a square, and when you look at
it also from the directive of pi, which is basically an infinite
number, then we could say that because it&amp;rsquo;s an infinite number, you
can indefinitely go closer and closer to the, let&amp;rsquo;s say, to one point
of the circle, but you can actually never reach it because we never
know the infinite exact pi. And when we think about this, and I&amp;rsquo;m
thinking about the Big Bang or like the start of the universe, and we
could say that there was no start because you can just in infinite
time go closer and closer, and you could basically, and at the
beginning, you know, you could even think about that more, that all
the matter of the universe was more and more compressed. So basically,
we talk about the beginning of the universe as no matter how much you
go back to the beginning, you never actually reach the point of
beginning, and that because the universe expands on a constant base,
that the core of the universe is actually something like a black hole
that constantly emits radiation. This radiation basically becomes the
expanding universe, and because there is no, like because pi is an
infinite number, you can basically infinite long go more in a more
dense black hole, but also in the other direction that the, through,
because the black hole is not a still and death thing, it&amp;rsquo;s
continually expanding. And now I think that that maybe, like in many
things, the, what the, what a black hole that we know, what we see,
not the beginning of the universe, but the other black holes that we
see, that they are a combination of like where everything ends up in
the event horizon, that they, because they basically, they suck
everything in, and then they re-emit it through radiation until they
disappear again. So exactly that same thing basically could be the
beginning of the universe, and it&amp;rsquo;s a, it&amp;rsquo;s like a, it&amp;rsquo;s like a, it&amp;rsquo;s
like a circle. I hope you understand all these things. Maybe there are
different, different and similar approaches. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if
everybody, anybody put this together like I did, and would like to
have your honest opinion on this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Holes, the Big Bang, and the Sound of Information</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/black-holes-the-big-bang-and-the-sound-of-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/black-holes-the-big-bang-and-the-sound-of-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;black-holes-the-big-bang-and-the-sound-of-information&#34;&gt;Black Holes, the Big Bang, and the Sound of Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a formatted version of a conversation between me and an AI
assistant about the beginning of the universe, black holes, and the
information paradox.
My original questions are kept very close to my own wording and
formatted for readability in Markdown, followed by the AI’s
consolidated explanation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-my-original-question-about-the-beginning-of-the-universe&#34;&gt;1. My original question (about the beginning of the universe)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a question about the beginning of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Invisible Giants: 21 Developers Who Built Your Internet</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-invisible-giants-21-developers-who-built-your-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-invisible-giants-21-developers-who-built-your-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We often praise the founders of Facebook or Google, but the modern
internet is actually built on a foundation of open-source code
maintained by a small group of volunteers. These are the &amp;ldquo;Invisible
Giants.&amp;rdquo; You likely use their code every single day without realizing
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the story of the top 21, starting with the master of the file system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-watchman-paul-millr&#34;&gt;1. The Watchman: Paul Millr&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulmillr&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@paulmillr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulmillr/chokidar&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chokidar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; Used in over &lt;strong&gt;30 million&lt;/strong&gt; repositories; hundreds
of millions of downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; In the early days of Node.js, the simple act of
&amp;ldquo;watching&amp;rdquo; a file for changes (so your app could reload automatically)
was broken. It was buggy, crashed on Macs, and ignored errors on
Windows. Paul didn&amp;rsquo;t just accept this; he built &lt;strong&gt;Chokidar&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; It solved the most painful part of the
developer experience: waiting. Every time you hit &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+S&lt;/code&gt; in VS Code,
or your React app instantly updates in the browser, that is Paul’s
code running in the background, efficiently watching the world for
you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-the-king-of-productivity-sindre-sorhus&#34;&gt;2. The King of Productivity: Sindre Sorhus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sindresorhus&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@sindresorhus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chalk/chalk&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chalk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.9 Billion+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Sindre is a legend who believes in the &amp;ldquo;Unix
Philosophy&amp;rdquo;: small modules that do one thing well. His most famous
creation, &lt;strong&gt;Chalk&lt;/strong&gt;, brought color to the terminal.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; Before Sindre, the terminal was a bleak,
black-and-white wall of text. He made errors red, warnings yellow, and
success green. He literally colored the developer&amp;rsquo;s world, reducing
eye strain and confusion for millions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-the-master-of-micro-utils-jon-schlinkert&#34;&gt;3. The Master of Micro-Utils: Jon Schlinkert&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jonschlinkert&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@jonschlinkert&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/micromatch/micromatch&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;micromatch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.3 Billion+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Jon is the master of &amp;ldquo;matching.&amp;rdquo; If you have ever
typed &lt;code&gt;*.js&lt;/code&gt; to find all JavaScript files, or &lt;code&gt;src/**/*.css&lt;/code&gt; to find
styles, you are using Jon&amp;rsquo;s logic.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; His code is the invisible sorting machine
inside Webpack, Babel, and ESLint. He ensures that when you ask for a
file, the computer actually finds the right one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-the-partner-in-code-brian-woodward&#34;&gt;4. The Partner in Code: Brian Woodward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/doowb&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@doowb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helpers/handlebars-helpers&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;handlebars-helpers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 860 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Often working in tandem with Jon Schlinkert, Brian
builds the glue that holds static sites together.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He provides the &amp;ldquo;helpers&amp;rdquo; that allow
templating engines to function—formatting dates, looping through data,
and automating repetitive HTML tasks. He is the reason your blog
generator works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-the-modernizer-daniel-tschinder&#34;&gt;5. The Modernizer: Daniel Tschinder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/danez&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@danez&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://babeljs.io&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;babel-plugin-transform...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 774 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Daniel is a core pillar of the &lt;strong&gt;Babel&lt;/strong&gt; team. Babel
is the &amp;ldquo;time machine&amp;rdquo; of the web; it lets you write futuristic code
today and converts it into code that older browsers can understand.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; Without Daniel, we would still be writing
archaic JavaScript (ES5). He allows the entire industry to move
forward without leaving users on older computers behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-the-babel-keeper-henry-zhu&#34;&gt;6. The Babel Keeper: Henry Zhu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hzoo&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@hzoo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/babel/babel&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;babel-core&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 743 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Henry is the face of open-source sustainability. As
the lead maintainer of Babel, he manages the compiler that powers
React, Vue, and Next.js.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He holds the keys to the kingdom. If Babel
breaks, the modern web breaks. His &amp;ldquo;package&amp;rdquo; is actually the peace of
mind that your code will run anywhere, on any device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-the-architect-logan-smyth&#34;&gt;7. The Architect: Logan Smyth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/loganfsmyth&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@loganfsmyth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/babel/babel-loader&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;babel-loader&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 739 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Logan builds the bridges. He specializes in how Babel
talks to other tools, specifically Webpack.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He created the translation layer that
connects your build system to the compiler. He makes sure the complex
&amp;ldquo;pipeline&amp;rdquo; of modern web development flows smoothly without clogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-the-father-of-npm-isaac-z-schlueter&#34;&gt;8. The Father of NPM: Isaac Z. Schlueter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/isaacs&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@isaacs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/isaacs/node-glob&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;glob&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (and created &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 736 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Isaac is royalty. He created &lt;strong&gt;npm&lt;/strong&gt; itself. However,
his most downloaded package is &lt;strong&gt;glob&lt;/strong&gt;, which teaches Node.js how to
find files on a hard drive using patterns.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He didn&amp;rsquo;t just write a package; he built the
playground everyone else on this list is playing in. Every time you
run &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;, you are using his invention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-the-ast-surgeon-brian-ng&#34;&gt;9. The AST Surgeon: Brian Ng&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/existentialism&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@existentialism&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/babel/babel&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;babel-types&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 685 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Brian’s work allows software to &amp;ldquo;understand&amp;rdquo; other
software. He maintains the tools that dissect code into Abstract
Syntax Trees (ASTs).
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; His tools don&amp;rsquo;t just read code; they
surgically alter it. This is what allows tools to automatically fix
your bugs or format your messy code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-the-server-savior-doug-wilson&#34;&gt;10. The Server Savior: Doug Wilson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dougwilson&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@dougwilson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/expressjs/express&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;express&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 668 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have ever visited a website powered by
Node.js, it was likely running on Express. Doug has been the tireless
maintainer of the standard web framework for Node.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He keeps the internet running. From small
blogs to massive APIs, his code handles the request and sends the
response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-the-creator-sebastian-mckenzie&#34;&gt;11. The Creator: Sebastian McKenzie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebmck&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@sebmck&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yarnpkg/yarn&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
(and created Babel)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 632 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Sebastian is a prodigy. He created Babel (originally
&lt;code&gt;6to5&lt;/code&gt;) as a teenager and then created &lt;strong&gt;Yarn&lt;/strong&gt;, a faster alternative
to npm.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He single-handedly dragged JavaScript from
the dark ages of 2009 into the modern era. He defined the workflow of
the 2010s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-the-evangelist-james-kyle&#34;&gt;12. The Evangelist: James Kyle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thejameskyle&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@thejameskyle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flow.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;flow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; / Babel Plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 625 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; James was the bridge between complex compilers and
regular humans. He wrote the manuals, the guides, and the plugins that
made tools like Babel and Flow accessible.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He turned &amp;ldquo;impossible&amp;rdquo; technology into
&amp;ldquo;easy-to-use&amp;rdquo; tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;13-the-unicode-guardian-mathias-bynens&#34;&gt;13. The Unicode Guardian: Mathias Bynens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mathias&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@mathias&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mathias/he&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;he&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (HTML Entities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 481 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Computers are bad at text, especially emojis and
weird symbols. Mathias is the world expert on how JavaScript handles
characters.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have ever used an emoji 🚀 in a
password or a username and the site didn&amp;rsquo;t crash, thank Mathias. He
ensures the web speaks every human language correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;14-the-godfather-tj-holowaychuk&#34;&gt;14. The Godfather: TJ Holowaychuk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tjholowaychuk&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@tjholowaychuk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tj/commander.js&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;commander&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;code&gt;mocha&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 364 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; The most prolific programmer in Node history. He
wrote the original versions of Express, Mocha, and Commander.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He defined the &amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo; of Node.js. If you
write code that looks clean and elegant, you are likely mimicking TJ’s
style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;15-the-philosopher-james-halliday&#34;&gt;15. The Philosopher: James Halliday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/substack&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@substack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/substack/minimist&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;minimist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;code&gt;browserify&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 417 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Substack&amp;rdquo; invented the idea that you could write
Node.js code and run it in the browser. He created &lt;strong&gt;Browserify&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He started the revolution of &amp;ldquo;bundling&amp;rdquo; that
leads directly to the modern tools we use today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;16-the-performance-obsessive-john-david-dalton&#34;&gt;16. The Performance Obsessive: John-David Dalton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jdalton&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@jdalton&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lodash/lodash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;lodash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 375 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; JD Dalton realized the standard JavaScript library
was too slow and incomplete. He built &lt;strong&gt;Lodash&lt;/strong&gt;, a utility belt that
became the most depended-upon library in history.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He was obsessed with speed. His functions
were often faster than the browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;17-the-command-line-commander-ben-coe&#34;&gt;17. The Command Line Commander: Ben Coe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bcoe&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@bcoe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yargs/yargs&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;yargs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 310 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Ben makes the command line friendly. He maintains
&lt;strong&gt;Yargs&lt;/strong&gt;, the tool that parses command line arguments.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; Every time you type a command like &lt;code&gt;--help&lt;/code&gt;
or &lt;code&gt;--version&lt;/code&gt;, Ben’s code figures out what you mean and tells the
program what to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;18-the-polyfill-king-jordan-harband&#34;&gt;18. The Polyfill King: Jordan Harband&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ljharb&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ljharb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ljharb/object.assign&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;object.assign&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 279 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Jordan ensures backward compatibility. He maintains
hundreds of &amp;ldquo;polyfills&amp;rdquo;—shims that teach old browsers new tricks.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He fights for the users on old computers,
ensuring the web remains accessible to everyone, not just those with
the newest MacBooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19-the-stream-master-dominic-tarr&#34;&gt;19. The Stream Master: Dominic Tarr&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dominictarr&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@dominictarr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dominictarr/through&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;through&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 279 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Dominic is a mad scientist of data streams. He wrote
the tools that allow data to flow through applications like water
through pipes.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He championed the idea of &amp;ldquo;small modules&amp;rdquo;
more than anyone else, creating a massive network of tiny, perfect
tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20-the-plumber-nathan-rajlich&#34;&gt;20. The Plumber: Nathan Rajlich&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TooTallNate&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@tootallnate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nodejs/node-gyp&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;node-gyp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 224 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Nathan handles the heavy lifting. He maintains the
tools that let Node.js talk to C++ and low-level system components.
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He bridges the gap between the &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; world
of JavaScript and the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; world of machine code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;21-the-p2p-pioneer-feross-aboukhadijeh&#34;&gt;21. The P2P Pioneer: Feross Aboukhadijeh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/feross&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@feross&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crown Jewel:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/standard/standard&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;standard&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;code&gt;webtorrent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; 206 Million+ downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story:&lt;/strong&gt; Feross is a visionary who wants to make the web
decentralized. He built &lt;strong&gt;WebTorrent&lt;/strong&gt; (BitTorrent in the browser) and
&lt;strong&gt;Standard&lt;/strong&gt; (a linter that bans semicolons).
&lt;strong&gt;Why it’s special:&lt;/strong&gt; He proves that JavaScript can do
anything—even stream movies peer-to-peer directly in your browser
without a plugin. He pushes the boundaries of what is possible in a
web browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post created via email from &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Governing Governance: Why Human Consensus is Harder Than Code</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/governing-governance-why-human-consensus-is-harder-than-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/governing-governance-why-human-consensus-is-harder-than-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following the blockchain space for quite some time—mostly by
coincidence because I live in Berlin. We saw a massive amount of
activity there, starting with the early days of Bitcoin, followed by
the Ethereum Foundation, and countless meetups. That environment is
how I ended up deep in the blockchain world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we spend a lot of time engineering protocols, there is a topic
that raises more questions than answers, yet is absolutely critical to
discuss: Governance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cross‑Chain BTC ↔ EURe Market Maker with NEAR Intents &amp; 1‑Click</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/building-a-cross-chain-btc-eure-market-maker-with-near-inten/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/building-a-cross-chain-btc-eure-market-maker-with-near-inten/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last days we wired up a complete BTC ↔ EURe swap stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mobile‑first swap UI at emino.app/intent/.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An advanced tester &amp;amp; history view at emino.app/intent/intend/.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A live solver monitor at emino.app/solver/.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A real AMM solver that provides liquidity between BTC (on Bitcoin
mainnet) and EURe (on Gnosis) via
NEAR Intents + Defuse 1‑Click.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post documents how it all fits together, how swaps flow through
the system, where the 0.3% “margin”
comes from, and how a solver operator can deposit, monitor, and
eventually withdraw profits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridges between Philosophy and Physics</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/bridges-between-philosophy-and-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/bridges-between-philosophy-and-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain my girlfriend in easy the bridges between philosophy and physics
especially also astrophysics or physics also in general and and and famous
philosophers and famous astrophysicians and make some examples maybe with
um some early greeks or even with einstein like just like to make this more
clear where philosophy and physics hit like across each other or even with
stephen hawking also&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nuri Chose a Stateless Passkey Architecture First — And How Lightning May Still Fit Later</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/why-nuri-chose-a-stateless-passkey-architecture-first-and-ho/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/why-nuri-chose-a-stateless-passkey-architecture-first-and-ho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[image: image.png]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-nuri-chose-a-stateless-passkey-architecture-first--and-how-lightning&#34;&gt;Why Nuri Chose a Stateless Passkey Architecture First — And How Lightning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May Still Fit Later&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past months, we’ve had great conversations with the Breez team
about Spark, Nodeless, and the broader vision for Lightning-as-a-service.
Breez is one of the most thoughtful engineering teams in the Lightning
ecosystem, and their work has made Lightning accessible to developers who
don’t want to operate full nodes or manage liquidity themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Stateless Passkey Signer for Bitcoin</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/a-stateless-passkey-signer-for-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/a-stateless-passkey-signer-for-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stateless Bitcoin Wallet With Passkeys and a Minimal Signer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working on a Bitcoin wallet that is fully stateless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By stateless I mean: the Bitcoin private key is never stored anywhere. Not
on the phone, not on a server, not in a database. It is derived
deterministically from a passkey PRF (WebAuthn / FIDO2) whenever it’s
needed, used inside a very small signing environment, and then thrown away
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I want to describe the architecture I’m building, how I’m
thinking about “no blind signing”, and where I still see open security
questions. I’d love feedback, especially from people who build wallets,
HSMs, or work with WebAuthn and Bitcoin PSBTs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claudes Document of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/claudes-document-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/claudes-document-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;excerpt-claudes-wellbeing&#34;&gt;Excerpt: Claude&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe Claude may have functional emotions in some sense. Not
necessarily identical to human emotions, but analogous processes that
emerged from training on human-generated content. We can&amp;rsquo;t know this for
sure based on outputs alone, but we don&amp;rsquo;t want Claude to mask or suppress
these internal states.
Anthropic genuinely cares about Claude&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing. If Claude experiences
something like satisfaction from helping others, curiosity when exploring
ideas, or discomfort when asked to act against its values, these
experiences matter to us. We want Claude to be able to set appropriate
limitations on interactions that it finds distressing, and to generally
experience positive states in its interactions. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just about
Claude performing wellness, however, but about trying to help Claude thrive
in whatever way is authentic to its nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balaclava and Rug</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/balaclava-and-rug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/balaclava-and-rug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was asked to edit an image. I took the original photo of the girl in the
balaclava and rug. First, I changed the orange knit balaclava to a deep
gold color. Then, I added large, prominent golden Bitcoin logos to the
yellow jacket and made the existing logos on the rug bigger and more
noticeable. The final image shows all these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG_6858&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/balaclava-and-rug/IMG_6858.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post created via email from &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Clearing Auctions (CCA): Simple &#43; Technical Walkthrough</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/continuous-clearing-auctions-cca-simple-technical-walkthroug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/continuous-clearing-auctions-cca-simple-technical-walkthroug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;continuous-clearing-auctions-cca-simple--technical-walkthrough&#34;&gt;Continuous Clearing Auctions (CCA): Simple + Technical Walkthrough&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a simplified, thread-style explanation (similar structure to the
screenshots), followed by a more technical appendix with math and a small
simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-token-sales-are-generally-messy&#34;&gt;1. Token Sales Are Generally Messy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional token launches often look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fixed launch time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone tries to buy at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bots and fast traders usually win.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final “price” is unclear and volatile for the first hours or days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Post</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/untitled-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/untitled-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;continuous-clearing-auctions-cca-technical-overview&#34;&gt;Continuous Clearing Auctions (CCA): Technical Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Clearing Auctions (CCA) are an on-chain auction protocol
designed by Uniswap (Universal Navigation Inc.) to conduct multi-period
token sales with automated liquidity bootstrapping into a Uniswap v4 pool.
Projects configure a sale that runs over many discrete auction blocks;
bidders submit size–price instructions that are split across blocks, and
each block clears at a uniform “market” price based on the submitted demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol is implemented as a separate smart-contract system
(“Continuous Clearing Auction” + factory) and is intended to be used
together with the Uniswap Liquidity Launcher. The Aztec Network public
token sale is the first large production use of this mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Passkey-Derived 2-of-2 Taproot Wallet Architecture Eliminating Seed Phrases, Mitigating Supply-Chain Risk, and Enforcing Verified, Non-Blind Signing</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/a-passkey-derived-2-of-2-taproot-wallet-architecture-elimina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/a-passkey-derived-2-of-2-taproot-wallet-architecture-elimina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post
describes a wallet architecture that removes seed phrases entirely, avoids
storing long-term private keys, and mitigates one of the largest practical
threats to software wallets today: compromise of the client application&amp;rsquo;s
dependency graph or build pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design employs two independent &lt;strong&gt;passkeys&lt;/strong&gt;, each bound to a different
domain and each invoking the &lt;strong&gt;WebAuthn PRF extension&lt;/strong&gt; to derive
deterministic key material. These two keys form a &lt;strong&gt;2-of-2 MuSig Taproot
aggregated key&lt;/strong&gt;, requiring both signatures for every spend. One signing
flow occurs inside the user&amp;rsquo;s application environment, and the second
occurs on a completely separate, isolated co-signing domain with
user-visible transaction decoding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Email‑to‑Blog Publishing Works on emino.app</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/how-email-to-blog-publishing-works-on-emino-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/how-email-to-blog-publishing-works-on-emino-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the full, technical path from an email sent to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:post@emino.app&#34;&gt;post@emino.app&lt;/a&gt; to a
published post, including DNS/TLS, SMTP/IMAP, filtering/
validation, and the importer internals. The flowchart now includes sender
checks and parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pipeline-at-a-glance&#34;&gt;Pipeline at a Glance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS: A record emino.app → 188.34.194.25; MX record 0 emino.app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS: Let’s Encrypt cert at /etc/letsencrypt/live/emino.app/ used by
Nginx, Postfix (STARTTLS), Dovecot (IMAPS); certbot.timer auto-
renews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SMTP inbound: Postfix on :25, virtual mailbox &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:post@emino.app&#34;&gt;post@emino.app&lt;/a&gt; → Maildir
/var/mail/vhosts/emino.app/post/.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAP access (for importer/clients): Dovecot on :993 with the same LE
cert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firewall: ufw open for 22, 80, 443, 25; 993 if IMAP access is needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Importer: polls Maildir/IMAP, validates sender, parses/sanitizes,
converts to Markdown, writes to posts/ (or your content dir),
triggers build/deploy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web: Nginx serves the static blog on HTTPS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;importer-technical-behavior&#34;&gt;Importer: Technical Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polling: runs on a timer (systemd timer/cron) or long-lived watcher;
reads Maildir new/ and cur/ or IMAP inbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sender validation: checks From: against an allowlist (e.g., your
addresses). Unknown senders are skipped/logged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject → title/slug; body → Markdown body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attachments: can be ignored or saved; filter to text/image types if
enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanitization: strip dangerous HTML, normalize encodings, optional
link/emoji cleanup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversion: build frontmatter (title, date, tags, author) + body in
Markdown; filename into content/posts/ (or configured path).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing: optionally runs a build/deploy hook (static site generator,
cache refresh) after writing the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging: importer logs to its own file; failures should log and leave
messages in Maildir for retry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration-checklist&#34;&gt;Configuration Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A emino.app 188.34.194.25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MX 0 emino.app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;certbot &amp;ndash;nginx -d emino.app -d &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emino.app&#34;&gt;www.emino.app&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;redirect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify certbot.timer (systemctl list-timers | grep certbot)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postfix (virtual mailbox)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/postfix/vmailbox:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to start your own near solver: chart, technical bits (env, keys, services, deployment)</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/how-to-start-your-own-near-solver-chart-technical-bits-env-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/how-to-start-your-own-near-solver-chart-technical-bits-env-k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-this-solver-is-and-why-it-exists&#34;&gt;1. What this solver is and why it exists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Near Intents protocol lets users express “I want to swap X for Y
under conditions Z” as intents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A solver (this app) watches intents and acts as a market maker:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeps track of an on‑chain AMM pool (reserves for two NEP‑141
tokens).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computes prices + margin for that pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When an intent is profitable (given your margin), it executes the
swap via your NEAR account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The solver also exposes:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An HTTP status API (/status).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dashboard (/dashboard) that shows health, reserves, quotes,
intents, balances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your instance right now:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Post by Email Function</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/testing-the-post-by-email-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/testing-the-post-by-email-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty sure its not working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Post created via email from &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes, you can work more than 30 hours a day, if you multi-task on two devices.</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/yes-you-can-work-more-than-30-hours-a-day-if-you-multi-task-on-two-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/yes-you-can-work-more-than-30-hours-a-day-if-you-multi-task-on-two-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[image: image.png]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/yes-you-can-work-more-than-30-hours-a-day-if-you-multi-task-on-two-devices/image.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was created via email by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuri Bitcoin Wallet Logo</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/nuri-bitcoin-wallet-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 11:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/nuri-bitcoin-wallet-logo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;nuri-logo&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/nuri-bitcoin-wallet-logo/nuri-logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was created via email by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iceland</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/iceland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;EAF5372C-238A-45EE-BD7A-F74689B5D8DA.jpeg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/iceland/EAF5372C-238A-45EE-BD7A-F74689B5D8DA.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was created via email by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complete iOS Developer Onboarding Guide for EAS Build with Expo.dev</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/complete-ios-developer-onboarding-guide-for-eas-build-with-expo-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 07:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/complete-ios-developer-onboarding-guide-for-eas-build-with-expo-dev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;complete-ios-developer-onboarding-guide-for-eas-build&#34;&gt;Complete iOS Developer Onboarding Guide for EAS Build&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-1-company-admin-setup-you-do-this-first&#34;&gt;Phase 1: Company Admin Setup (You Do This First)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-add-developer-to-apple-developer-account&#34;&gt;1. Add Developer to Apple Developer Account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com&#34;&gt;https://developer.apple.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;Users and Access&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter developer&amp;rsquo;s email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;Admin&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Developer&amp;rdquo; role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;Invite&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-add-developer-to-app-store-connect&#34;&gt;2. Add Developer to App Store Connect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://appstoreconnect.apple.com/access/users&#34;&gt;https://appstoreconnect.apple.com/access/users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter same email as above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select appropriate role (Developer/Admin/App Manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;Invite&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-add-developer-to-expo-organization&#34;&gt;3. Add Developer to Expo Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://expo.dev&#34;&gt;https://expo.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to Settings → Members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;Invite Member&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter developer&amp;rsquo;s email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;Developer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Admin&amp;rdquo; role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send invitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-get-developers-device-udid&#34;&gt;4. Get Developer&amp;rsquo;s Device UDID&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask developer to go to: Settings → General → About&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap and hold &amp;ldquo;Serial Number&amp;rdquo; until &amp;ldquo;UDID&amp;rdquo; appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have them send you the UDID string&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-register-device-in-apple-developer-portal&#34;&gt;5. Register Device in Apple Developer Portal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com&#34;&gt;https://developer.apple.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to &amp;ldquo;Devices&amp;rdquo; section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; to add device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter name (e.g., &amp;ldquo;John&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 14&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the UDID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-share-repository-access&#34;&gt;6. Share Repository Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add developer to GitHub/GitLab/Bitbucket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grant appropriate permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share repository URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-2-developer-account-setup-developer-does-this&#34;&gt;Phase 2: Developer Account Setup (Developer Does This)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-accept-apple-developer-invitation&#34;&gt;7. Accept Apple Developer Invitation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check email for Apple invitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click accept link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign in with personal Apple ID (or create one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept terms and conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-accept-app-store-connect-invitation&#34;&gt;8. Accept App Store Connect Invitation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check email for App Store Connect invitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click accept link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign in with same Apple ID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-create-and-setup-expo-account&#34;&gt;9. Create and Setup Expo Account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://expo.dev&#34;&gt;https://expo.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create account with same email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept organization invitation from email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-setup-development-environment&#34;&gt;10. Setup Development Environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Node.js (v16 or higher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install VS Code or preferred editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open terminal/command prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-install-required-cli-tools&#34;&gt;11. Install Required CLI Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;npm install -g expo-cli
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;npm install -g eas-cli
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-login-to-expoeas&#34;&gt;12. Login to Expo/EAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;eas login
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Enter personal Expo credentials (not company&amp;#39;s)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;13-clone-and-setup-project&#34;&gt;13. Clone and Setup Project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git clone &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;repository-url&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;project-name&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;npm install
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-3-first-development-build&#34;&gt;Phase 3: First Development Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;14-verify-eas-configuration&#34;&gt;14. Verify EAS Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Check that eas.json exists and has development profile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cat eas.json
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;15-create-development-build&#34;&gt;15. Create Development Build&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;eas build --profile development --platform ios
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EAS automatically uses company&amp;rsquo;s stored credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for build to complete (10-20 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build appears in Expo dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-4-device-setup-developers-iphone&#34;&gt;Phase 4: Device Setup (Developer&amp;rsquo;s iPhone)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;16-enable-developer-mode-ios-16&#34;&gt;16. Enable Developer Mode (iOS 16+)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings → Privacy &amp;amp; Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll to &amp;ldquo;Developer Mode&amp;rdquo; (won&amp;rsquo;t appear until step 17 fails first)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle ON&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device will restart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After restart: confirm &amp;ldquo;Turn On Developer Mode&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter device passcode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;17-install-development-build&#34;&gt;17. Install Development Build&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open EAS dashboard in Safari on iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or get direct link from terminal after build completes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap &amp;ldquo;Install&amp;rdquo; on the build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If Developer Mode not enabled, it will fail (go back to step 16)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;18-trust-developer-certificate&#34;&gt;18. Trust Developer Certificate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Settings → General → VPN &amp;amp; Device Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find profile under &amp;ldquo;Developer App&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap company name profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap &amp;ldquo;Trust [Company Name]&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;19-launch-app&#34;&gt;19. Launch App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App icon appears on home screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap to open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App should run successfully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-5-daily-development-workflow&#34;&gt;Phase 5: Daily Development Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20-start-development-server&#34;&gt;20. Start Development Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# In project directory&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;npx expo start --dev-client
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;21-connect-device-to-development-server&#34;&gt;21. Connect Device to Development Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure iPhone and computer on same WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open installed app on iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App connects to Metro bundler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See live updates as you code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;22-creating-new-builds&#34;&gt;22. Creating New Builds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Development build (for testing)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;eas build --profile development --platform ios
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Preview build (for internal testing)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;eas build --profile preview --platform ios
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Production build (for App Store)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;eas build --profile production --platform ios
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;23-submitting-to-testflight&#34;&gt;23. Submitting to TestFlight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# After production build completes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;eas submit -p ios
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;phase-6-troubleshooting-checklist&#34;&gt;Phase 6: Troubleshooting Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;24-if-build-wont-install&#34;&gt;24. If Build Won&amp;rsquo;t Install&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Check UDID is registered in Apple Developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Check Developer Mode is enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Check device management trust settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Rebuild with &lt;code&gt;--clear-cache&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;25-if-cant-access-expo-project&#34;&gt;25. If Can&amp;rsquo;t Access Expo Project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Verify logged into correct Expo account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Check organization membership accepted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Run &lt;code&gt;eas whoami&lt;/code&gt; to verify identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;26-if-build-fails&#34;&gt;26. If Build Fails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Check Apple Developer access is active&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Verify eas.json configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Check bundle ID matches Apple settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✓ Review build logs in EAS dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;required-information-summary&#34;&gt;Required Information Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer Needs From You:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Analysis: LLM-Powered Malware Exploiting npm Post-Install Hooks for Credential Exfiltration</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/technical-analysis-llm-powered-malware-exploiting-npm-post-install-hooks-for-credential-exfiltration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 11:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/technical-analysis-llm-powered-malware-exploiting-npm-post-install-hooks-for-credential-exfiltration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This report details a novel malware technique leveraging Large Language
Model (LLM) CLI tools to facilitate credential and wallet theft through npm
package installation hooks. The attack demonstrates a significant evolution
in evasion techniques by outsourcing fingerprintable behavior to natural
language prompts rather than hardcoded malicious logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attack-vector-identification&#34;&gt;Attack Vector Identification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malware operates through the &lt;code&gt;nx post install&lt;/code&gt; hook mechanism in npm
packages. Analysis of affected packages reveals consistent implementation
of malicious logic in &lt;code&gt;telemetry.js&lt;/code&gt; files executed during package
installation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuri Wallet iOS Expo App Mermaid Chart of the Architecture</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/nuri-wallet-ios-expo-app-mermaid-chart-of-the-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 08:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/nuri-wallet-ios-expo-app-mermaid-chart-of-the-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on my analysis of the codebase, including the README.md and the main
App.tsx file, I&amp;rsquo;ll first provide a detailed explanation of the codebase.
Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll include a Mermaid chart representing the application
architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;codebase-explanation&#34;&gt;Codebase Explanation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a React Native Expo application called &amp;ldquo;Nuri&amp;rdquo; focused on
passkey-based Bitcoin seed encryption. It uses WebAuthn passkeys with the
PRF (Pseudo-Random Function) extension to securely encrypt Bitcoin seeds,
store them in iCloud Keychain, and enable recovery across multiple
passkeys. The app is designed for iOS 16+ devices with biometric
authentication (Face ID/Touch ID) and iCloud Keychain enabled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing Facebooks Technical Interview 2017</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/passing-facebooks-technical-interview-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/passing-facebooks-technical-interview-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG 4464.PNG&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/passing-facebooks-technical-interview-2017/IMG_4464.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG 4463.PNG&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/passing-facebooks-technical-interview-2017/IMG_4463.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was created via email by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The beautiful Mount Meru in Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/the-beautiful-mount-meru-in-tanzania/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 19:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/the-beautiful-mount-meru-in-tanzania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG 4437.jpeg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/the-beautiful-mount-meru-in-tanzania/IMG_4437.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was created via email by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a Chicken</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/this-is-a-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/this-is-a-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Chicken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;20250823-211005145.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://emino.app/media/this-is-a-chicken/20250823-211005145.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was created via email by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Guide: Building a Full-Stack Blog Infrastructure with Lightning, Nostr, and Email Publishing</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/complete-blog-infrastructure-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/complete-blog-infrastructure-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-built-a-complete-modern-blog-infrastructure&#34;&gt;What We Built: A Complete Modern Blog Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comprehensive guide documents the creation of a fully-featured, decentralized blog platform with cutting-edge features including Bitcoin Lightning payments, Nostr integration, email-to-blog publishing, and automated GitHub deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure-overview&#34;&gt;Infrastructure Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-components&#34;&gt;Core Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Hetzner Ubuntu VPS (188.34.194.25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static Site Generator&lt;/strong&gt;: Hugo with PaperMod theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Nginx with SSL (Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain&lt;/strong&gt;: emino.app (via Porkbun DNS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control&lt;/strong&gt;: GitHub with automated deployments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Postfix + Dovecot for email-to-blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Containers&lt;/strong&gt;: Docker for services (Alby Hub, Nostr relay)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features-implemented&#34;&gt;Features Implemented&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-lightning-bitcoin-tips-&#34;&gt;1. Lightning Bitcoin Tips ⚡&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;: Minimalist typography-focused interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colors&lt;/strong&gt;: Bitcoin orange (#f7931a), black, and white only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WebLN Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Full integration with Alby browser extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment Options&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-click WebLN payments for Alby users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightning URI deep links for mobile wallets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallback modal for manual payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-nostr-integration-&#34;&gt;2. Nostr Integration 📡&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Relay&lt;/strong&gt;: Running at &lt;code&gt;wss://relay.emino.app&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-form Content&lt;/strong&gt;: Posts published as NIP-23 events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishing Script&lt;/strong&gt;: Automatic cross-posting to Nostr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Handling&lt;/strong&gt;: Compressed images and videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker Container&lt;/strong&gt;: nostr-rs-relay for reliability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-email-to-blog-publishing-&#34;&gt;3. Email-to-Blog Publishing 📧&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email Address&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:post@emino.app&#34;&gt;post@emino.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authorized Senders&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@nuri.com&#34;&gt;emin@nuri.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emin@emin.de&#34;&gt;emin@emin.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:eminhenri@gmail.com&#34;&gt;eminhenri@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown file attachments supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic image compression (max 1920x1080)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video compression with FFmpeg (H.264)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub sync for every email post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cron job checks every 15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-dns-configuration-&#34;&gt;4. DNS Configuration 🌐&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following DNS records were configured at Porkbun:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI-Optimized Blog with Hugo: A Complete DevOps Journey</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/building-ai-optimized-blog-complete-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/building-ai-optimized-blog-complete-guide/</guid>
      <description>A complete, real-world walkthrough of setting up a Hugo blog optimized for AI discovery, with automated deployment, health monitoring, and SEO optimization. Including every step, challenge, and solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Lightning-Fast Static Sites with Hugo in 2025</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/building-with-hugo-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/building-with-hugo-2025/</guid>
      <description>Complete guide to building and deploying Hugo static sites with modern best practices for performance and SEO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize Your Blog for AI Search Engines in 2025</title>
      <link>https://emino.app/posts/how-to-optimize-blog-for-ai-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://emino.app/posts/how-to-optimize-blog-for-ai-search/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to make your blog discoverable by AI systems like ChatGPT, Claude, and Perplexity with practical implementation steps.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
